Finding Aid for Carnegie Corporation of New York. Aging Society Project (1982-1986) records
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Book File
  - Authors Conference
    - June 11, 1984
      - Summary (Box 11)
      - Transcript, 4 folders (Box 11)
    - January 23-25, 1985
      - General, 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Transcript, 10 folders (Box 11)
  - Blackburn, Sara re editorial work, April-July, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Book Agents, March-October, 1984; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Book Call, March-May, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Book Endorsements, September, 1985-March, 1986 (Box 11)
  - Book Proposal for Publishers, August-December, 1984; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Book title Suggestions, undated, 1984; 1985 (Box 11)
  - Byrd Press (Box 11)
  - Chapter Drafts
    - Achenbaum, W. Andrew, 1984; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Avorn, Jerry, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Birren, James E., 1985; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Buchanan, Constance H., 1984-1985; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Callahan, Daniel, 1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Davis, Karen, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Gibson, Rose, 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Hagestad, Gunhild O., 1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Moody, Harry R., 1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
    - Morrison, Malcolm H., 1985; 4 folders (Box 12)
    - Neugarten, Bernice L. and Dail A. Neugarten, 1985; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Palmer, John L. and Stephanie G. Gould, 1985; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Pifer, Alan, 1984-1985; 6 folders (Box 13)
    - Pifer, Alan and D. Lydia Bronte, 1984-1986; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Richman, Harold A. and Matthew W. Stagner, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Riley, Matilda White and John W. Riley, 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Rossi, Alice S., 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Siegel, Jacob S. and Cynthia M. Taeuber, 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Teitelbaum, Michael S., 1984-1985; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Torres-Gii, Fernando, 1984-1985; 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Wynne, Edward A., 1984-1985; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Chapter Titles, October-November, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Chicago Tribune Series-"The Graying of America,", December, 1985 (Box 14)
    (also includes later articles based on series)
  - Copyright, November-December, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Cutting the Size of the Manuscript, August-November, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Daedalus
    - Correspondence with Stephen Graubard, June 1983-May, 1986; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Lilla, September 1985-January, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Reception, July 14, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Galley Lists, November 1985-January, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Letters to Authors
    - October 22, 1984 (Box 14)
    - January 8, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Marketing, March-June, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Miscellanea, 1984-1986 (Box 14)
  - Norton
    - Bill Rusin Correspondence, January-April, 1986 (Box 14)
    - Carol Smith Correspondence, January 1985-October, 1986; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Contract, February-March, 1985 (Box 14)
  - Order Sheets (Box 14)
  - Outlines, October 1983-November, 1985; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Press Conference and Reception, June 4, 1986; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Publicity
    - (Lisl Cade3, April 1984-January, 1985 (Box 15)
    - February, 1985-March, 1986 (Box 15)
    - April-December, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Alan Pifer Correspondence, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Arkansas, 1984 (Box 15)
    - Cleveland Trip, September 17-18, 1986 (Box 15)
    - David Wilson Article on Westchester Project, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Elizabeth Mehren Article in the L.A. Times, June, 1986 (Box 15)
    - "Firing Line"-William F. Buckley, April 2, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Joan Beek Interview with Alan Pifer, June, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Philadelphia Trip (Box 15)
    - Radio and TV Appearances, June, 1986-December, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Publishers, October 1983-January, 1985; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Reference Articles Sent to Authors, July 23, 1984 (Box 15)
  - Resumes of Advisors (Box 15)
  - Review of Book
    - March-November, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, May-June, 1986 (Box 15)
    - New York Times Book Review, May 25, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Table of Contents and Page Count (Box 15)
  - Television Talk Shows, May, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Unassigned Chapters, February 15, 1984 (Box 15)
- Conference File, 1983-1984
  The Conference File, boxes 16-19, covers the period 1983-1984. It contains correspondence, notes, participants lists, summaries, transcripts, agendas, reports, proceedings and publications concerning the conferences sponsored by the Aging Society Project. The conferences cover aging as it affects women, children, Blacks, Hispanics, the labor force, education, and other societies. This material is arranged chronologically by conference and then alphabetically by topic. Records from the conference "Population Aging in the United States and Japan: National and International Implications" were not transferred as part of this accession of materials.
  - Consequences of an Aging Society, February 7-8, 1983
    - Correspondence, December 1982-February, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Notes (Box 16)
    - Participants Lists (Box 16)
    - Summary (Box 16)
    - Transcript, 4 folders (Box 16)
  - Values in an Aging Society, April 27-29, 1983
    - Agendas (Box 16)
    - Biographies of Participants (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, February-July, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Eastern Sociological Society Panel on Values and the Humanities, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Gallup Surveys (Box 16)
    - Notebook (Box 16)
    - Notes (Box 16)
    - Papers Prepared by Participants (Box 16)
    - Participants Lists (Box 16)
    - Publications and Professional Papers, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Report on American Values and the Elderly (Box 16)
    - Summary (Box 16)
  - Intergenerational Equity Mini-Conference, May 3, 1983; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Women's Issues in the Aging Society, June 27, 1983
    - Correspondence, May-December, 1983 (Box 16)
    - Notes (Box 16)
    - Participants List (Box 16)
    - Printed Materials (Box 16)
    - Report (Box 16)
    - Transcript (Box 16)
  - Human Resource Implications of an Aging Workforce, September 21-23, 1983
    - Agenda (Box 17)
    - Benefits Tables, 1970-1979 (Box 17)
    - Bibliography-Late-Life Health Behavior and Self-Care (Box 17)
    - Biographies of Participants (Box 17)
    - Correspondence
      - February-July, 1983 (Box 17)
      - August, 1983 (Box 17)
      - September 1-26, 1983 (Box 17)
      - September 27-30, 1983 (Box 17)
      - October 1983-February, 1985 (Box 17)
    - Expenses (Box 17)
    - Notes (Box 17)
    - Papers
      - Barocas, Victor S., "Mature Worker Unit Policy Evaluation Study Design: A Working Draft" (Box 17)
      - Fullerton, Howard N., Jr., "The Aging Labor Force: 1950-1995" (Box 17)
      - Kahn, Robert L., "Productive Behavior Through the Life Course" (Box 17)
      - Morrison, Malcolm H. and Victor S. Barocas, "The Aging Work Force-Human Resource Implications" (Box 17)
    - Participants Lists
      - Undated (Box 17)
      - July-November, 1983 (Box 17)
    - Proceedings and Collected Papers, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Proceedings and Collected Papers-Published Report
      - Summary, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Transcript, 4 folders (Box 17)
  - What Children and Elders Have to Offer Each Other in an Aging Society, January 21-23, 1984
    - Correspondence, January 1983-June, 1984 (Box 17)
    - Final Report (Box 17)
    - General (Box 17)
    - Notes (Box 17)
    - Participants Lists, January, 1984 (Box 17)
    - Printed Material and Professional Papers (Box 18)
    - Transcripts, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Societal Aging in the United States and Western Europe, June 18-22, 1984
    - Agendas (Box 18)
    - Biographies of Participants (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, June 1983-November, 1984; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - General (Box 18)
    - Grant Application (Box 18)
    - Notes (Box 18)
    - Papers by Participants, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Participants Lists, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Publications and Background Material, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Report, 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Suggested Participants, 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Blacks in an Aging Society, October 16, 1984
    - Correspondence, August 1984-March, 1986; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - General (Box 18)
    - Participants Lists (Box 18)
    - Proceedings, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Proceedings, 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Report, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Hispanics in an Aging Society, October 24-25, 1984
    - Correspondence, March, 1984-July, 1985 (Box 19)
    - General (Box 19)
    - Participants Lists (Box 19)
    - Report, 4 folders (Box 19)
    - Transcript, 3 folders (Box 19)
  - Education in an Aging Society, November 8-9, 1984
    - Agendas (Box 19)
    - Correspondence, July 1984-November, 1984 (Box 19)
    - Notes (Box 19)
    - Participants Lists (Box 19)
    - Printed Materials (Box 19)
    - Report (Box 19)
    - Transcripts, 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Proposed Conferences
    - Health Care Conference (Box 19)
    - Intergenerational Equity Conference (Box 19)
    - National and International Implications of Population Aging in the United States and Japan (Box 19)